Ali Rahimi



Esfahan/Iran +989135732644 alirahimii@protonmail.com

github in linkedin

SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer. Assign me with some tasks, I'll find the solutions and get it done. Experienced in development of complex Android Applications with the new stacks such as Kotlin, JetPackComponents (MVVM/ROOM/DATABINDING/etc), Dependency Injection(Dagger), Dataflow(Retrofit/Moshi/Coroutines) and etc.

EDUCATION

Isfahan Univercity of Technology

2013-2019

B.Sc. in Software Engineering

• Course Work: Advanced Mathematics and Physics, Software Engineering Principals(Design, Architecture, OOP, etc) Data Structure, OS Architecture, Theory of Formal Languages(Compilers, Automata), Databases, Computer Networks, Software Engineering, IT Engineering, Statistics, AI, Computer Graphics, Economics, Microprocessors and etc.

EXPERIENCE

PulseCo, Freelancer

Sep 2014 - March 2015/IR

Full front-end Android Developer

• The very first application I wrote with Android SDK. Artistic Pantomime Game/Application with cool UX and UI written in Java for android 2.1 to 4.0. The APK still works perfectly in android 10!

PulseCo, Freelancer, IR

May 2015 - August 2015 / IR

iOS Developer

I learned native iOS development with Swift by developing an existing android application to iOS. I really liked and appreciated the Apple Architecture Design guidelines (MVC)

TreeCo, Freelancer

Nov 2015 - July 2016/ IR

Full front-end Android Developer

• Android Online and Offline Game/Application written in Java. Key features: Notifications for everything, Restfull and Web Sockets Communication With Server, Registration/Friend Management/Chat, Encrypted Coin System, Analytics and etc.

Remote Freelancer

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016 / Malaysia

Front-end Android Developer

• Smart Pledge System designed and implemented for funding a political party in malaysia. I implemented some basic data flow, authentication, subscribing to a payment plan and actual paying functionality with PayPall or Cards.

Bachelor Project

March 2019 - August 2019 / IR

FullStack Developer

• Persian Sign Language Learning Assistant Native Android Application for children with the use of Visual Learning techniques by providing videos and images. New learning modules could be added to the existing app from a node js server.

Remote Freelancer

August 2019 - October 2020 / EU

Full front-end Android and Android TV Developer

Stack: Kotlin,MVVM,Databiding,RoomDB,WorkManager,Retrofit,Dependency Injection(Dagger) and Kotlin Coroutines. Worked and communicated in English with a European company.

SKILLS _

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES
SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT
FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

Experienced: Python | Swift **Familiar:** Javascript | Objective-C | Bash | Java | Scheme

Jupyter | Matplotplib | Numpy | Pandas | Scikit-learn | Gym | PyTorch | Tensorflow

Programming Paradigms | GIT | CLI | Agile Methodology | DevOps Lifecycles

 IOS PROGRAMMING
 RxSwift
 PromiseKit
 CocoaPods
 Autolayout/DSLs

LANGUAGES Native: Turkish Fluent: English Beginner: German

EXTRA

- Mauris ut leo. Cras viverra metus rhoncus sem.
- Nulla et lectus vestibulum urna fringilla ultrices. Phasellus eu tellus sit amet tortor gravida placerat.
- Integer sapien est, iaculis in, pretium quis, viverra ac, nunc. Praesent eget sem vel leo ultrices bibendum.